Kelsey Flynn

Web Developer with strong organizational, analytical, design and communication ability that commits to continuous learning. Experience in education & HR/compliance creates a strong grasp of liaising with both businesses and users of all backgrounds, regarding deliverables.

Calgary, AB, T2V E34 (403) 808-2573 kelseyflynnn@gmail.com

GitHub: /KSFlynn007 **LinkedIn:** /kelseysflynn

PROJECTS

Code Club — Full-Stack Developer

February 2021 - March 2021

- Architected an event meet-up PWA built with React; used Google Calendar API and Amazon AWS Lambda serverless platform to fetch events.
- Developed with TDD techniques, FP & OOP paradigms, and data visualization.

myFlix DB — Full-Stack Developer

December 2020 - January 2021

- REST API created with MongoDB Atlas, for a future online movie database application. Constructed endpoints in server-side code for all CRUD requests.
- Established security processes including password hashing encryption, JWT authentication and CORS.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry, Remote — Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

November 2020 - June 2021 (Expected)

 Created various projects as a full-stack developer; handled all stages from planning to final deployment, and through this developed capability in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React and React Native.

University of Calgary, Calgary, AB — Bachelor of Arts

September 2012 - April 2016

Linguistics Major, Management and Society (Business) Minor

- Studied data collection and optimization to further extrapolating patterns and rulesets.
- Developed interpersonal, creative and presentational skills; organized and delegated sections of projects to individuals based on abilities to create cohesive teams.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML

CSS/SCSS

JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks:jQuery, React, React Native,
Bootstrap, Foundation

Paradigms: Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming

DEVELOPER TOOLS

Programs: GitHub/Git Version Control, Postman, pgAdmin 4, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Visual Studio Code

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud Servers: Amazon AWS

Hosting: Github Pages, Heroku, Netlify

OS: Windows/Powershell, Linux/Ubuntu

Chrome Tools: DevTools, Lighthouse, Redux DevTools

EXPERIENCE

Franworks, Calgary, AB & Remote — HR & Compliance Administrator

April 2019 - November 2020

- Oversaw departmental data collection and document editing, auditing & legal researching.
- Analyzed data for multiple departments with little background knowledge given and created reports summarizing findings.
- Led all licensing and Worker's Compensation accounts in North America coordinating with governmental agencies, remote representatives and third party facilities.
- Demonstrated ability to coordinate with different companies, update with kanban management, learn new systems without guidance and utilization of data analysis to improve processes.

Franworks, Calgary, AB & Remote — Receptionist/Office Manager

March 2018 - November 2020

• Demonstrated ability to handle multiple department's needs, represent a brand to external clients, and take leadership roles for neglected projects.

The Reading Foundation, Calgary, AB — Clinician

May 2015 - April 2017

- Taught remedial lessons to students from a wide variety of cultural and language backgrounds; implemented behavioral management for students with learning disabilities.
- Prepared program sessions by referencing clinical notes during sessions and external resources.
- Demonstrated ability to work in a large team to tailor programs to individual files, strategizing cooperatively on cases, and making continuous improvements to lessons without advanced notice.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Private Tutor — *Paris*, *France*

September 2017 - December 2017

 Demonstrated ability to take on short-term positions and reach goals within deadline.

SKILLS

Written & Verbal Communication

Problem Solving

Analytical thinker

Organized & Methodical

Time Management

Team Leadership & Project Management

MS Office, G-Suite applications, Survey Monkey, Formstack, Basecamp & Monday.com